Xinhe Zhang

Mobile: (412) 273-0270 Email: xinhez96@gmail.com Website: https://xinhez.github.io

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/xinhez

STATEMENT

After two years of industry experience and two years in academic research labs, I have found my interest at the intersection of computer engineering and machine learning, especially as they apply to healthcare. My ultimate career goal is to lead my own research team to work at the frontier of AI healthcare technologies, in academia or industry.

EDUCATION

Carnegie Mellon University

Pittsburgh, PA

Master of Science in Electrical and Computer Engineering; GPA: 4.0 / 4.0

Dec 2020

Bachelor of Science in Electrical and Computer Engineering with University Honors; GPA: 3.68/4.0

May 2018

- Carnegie Institute of Technology Research Honors

RESEARCH PROJECTS

Synthetic Data for Deep Neural Networks

Pittsburgh, PA

Carnegie Mellon University Robotics Institute Navigation Laboratory

Sep 2019 - Present

• Created synthetic road scene images with Carla simulator and Autodesk Maya and trained neural networks in Detectron2 and PyTorch to detect objects in real images for autonomous driving tasks.

Safety Analysis of Transcranial Electrical Stimulation

Pittsburgh, PA

Carnegie Mellon University Grover's Laboratory

Sep 2019 - Present

• Simulated human head FEM models in COMSOL and assessed safety measurements for transcranial electric stimulation as part of a novel human brain stimulation project.

Diabetic Retinopathy Detection with Deep Learning

Pittsburgh, PA

Carnegie Mellon University Engineering Research Accelerator

Sep 2017 - May 2018

• Designed and developed a machine learning pipeline that first captured the underlying domain knowledge from retina fundus images and classified processed results.

Wireless Backend for Virtual Reality Devices

Pittsburgh, PA

Carnegie Mellon CyLab Security and Privacy Institute

Sep 2016 - Dec 2016

• Researched on the implementation of a wireless backend for the Oculus hardware device.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Guangdong 999 Brain Hospital

Guangzhou, China

Assistant to the Dean

Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

- Processed thousands of patient data entries into a machine-readable format for research purposes.
- Evaluated million-dollar machine learning products by analyzing embedded technologies for the Vice President.

Duolingo, Inc

Pittsburgh, PA

Android Developer

Nov 2018 - May 2019

- Collaborated with the China team and communicated with vendors to establish push notification in China.
- Introduced UI/UX improvements to the purchasing screens on Android and boosted membership sales.

Expii, Inc
Engineer Intern

Pittsburgh, PA

Aug 2018 - Oct 2018

• Implemented changes across the stack and collaborated with the content team to boost SEO results to Google Search's first-page ranking by editing embedded metadata as the sole engineer.

Facebook, Inc Seattle, WA

Software Engineer Intern

May 2018 - Aug 2018

• Built a full-stack web app that queries from databases and collectively displays the results with user-specified parameters as part of the Facebook Analytics Automated Insights.

Google, Inc

Mountain View, CA; Boulder, CO

Software Engineering Intern

May 2017 - Aug 2017

- Created a web data visualization to compute logic relationships for 150 monthly professional users.
- Improved filtering methods and data animation by manipulating D3.js for 100 daily professional users.

Engineering Practicum Intern

May 2016 - Aug 2016

- Deployed a C++ backend server that retrieves data from a large, spatially indexed table for geospatial data.
- Researched and crafted an interactive web display of 3d geospatial data with WebGL and Google Maps API.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Towards Robust Blood Vessel Segmentation for Retinal Images

Mar 2020 - May 2020

Added domain discriminator to predict the domain of given feature map to improve the cross-data set testing
performance on the state-of-the-art model IterNet.

Second Language Acquisition Modeling with Deep Learning

Sep 2019 - Dec 2019

• Adapted and analyzed various deep learning models to predict errors second language learners are likely to make in the future and beat the given baseline 85.6%.

Experimenting Time-Space-Aware Memory for Deep Reinforcement Learning

Mar 2018 - May 2018

• Examined time-based and location-based structure to the replay memory and combined the recent-experience-based approach in Memory Networks and coordinate-based approach in Neural Map.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Deep Reinforcement Learning (Teaching Assistant)

Fall 2020

Signals and Systems (Head Grader)

Spring 2020

Signals and Systems (Grader)

Fall 2016, Spring 2018, Fall 2019

Fundamentals of Programming (Teaching Assistant)

Fall 2015, Spring 2016, Spring 2017

Principles of Computing (Teaching Assistant)

Summer 2015

LEADERSHIP

Co-Founder

Talent Pool (Startup)

IEEE-Eta Kappa Nu Honor Society Sigma Chapter

Oct 2017 - May 2019

Corresponding Secretary and Elected Member

CMU Summit on U.S.-China Innovation and Entrepreneurship

May 2017 - Aug 2018 Feb 2017 - Aug 2018

Carnegie Mellon University

Co-President and Panel Director

College Reading and Learning Association Certified Level 2: Advanced Tutor

Feb 2015 - May 2018

SKILLS

Languages: Python, Javascript, Kotlin, C/C++, SQL, LATEX

Tools: PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras, Detectron, React, Redux, Express, AWS, COMSOL